Andrea Cristina Bravo Balado

Address: 1068LH, Amsterdam E-mail: andreacbravob@gmail.com

Website: andreabravo.me
Nationalities: Venezuelan and Spanish

Phone: +31644089932 Birth date: 03/11/1986

I am a junior software engineer, about to obtain my MSc degree in Artificial Intelligence from Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam. Before moving to the Netherlands, I worked for two years as a software engineer in a Venezuelan banking institution. Communication is one of my strongest qualities and I believe in responsibility and in solving problems creatively, paying close attention to each and every detail. I am looking forward to continuing my professional career in a role where I can combine semantic web, linked data or information retrieval with software development, in a dynamic and learning environment.

Education

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam | Amsterdam, Netherlands

2010-2014 (expected)

MS in Artificial Intelligence, Knowledge Technology and Intelligent Internet Applications specialization.

My master thesis consists of linking ship records from the Nordelijke Monsterrollen collection (which contains data of ships and ship movements from the northern regions of the Netherlands from 1803 to 1937) with unstructured noisy text, obtained by means of OCR (Optical Character Recognition) from the Koninklijke Bibliotheek newspaper collection using techniques from information retrieval, machine learning and domain-specific features.

Universidad Rafael Belloso Chacín | Maracaibo, Venezuela

2004-2008

BS in Software Engineering.

Graduated with Cum Laude honors.

Extra curricular activities: Centro de Transferencia de Tecnología (Technology Transfer Center) and IglURBE: University's linux user group.

Experience

Volunteer English teacher | Casa Migrante Amsterdam

April 2014 – Present | Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Teacher for Spanish-speaking adults in the Netherlands.
- Planning course content and lessons.

Editor | Amsterdamdo

March 2011 – Present | Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Travel blog about Amsterdam.
- Targeted to Spanish-speaking travelers.
- Personalized travel itineraries for visits in Amsterdam.

Software and support engineer | Desarrollo Fintec de Costa Rica

May 2008 – February 2010 | San José, Costa Rica and Maracaibo, Venezuela

- Support and development of an inter-banking application that manages incoming and outgoing direct debits and credits between the bank and the Central Bank of Venezuela.
- Worked with Banco Occidental de Descuento (BOD) and Banfoandes (now Banco Bicentenario) in Venezuela and shortly with Scotiabank in Costa Rica.
- Developed with Java EE, Spring and Hibernate using Eclipse. Deployed on Apache Tomcat.
- Worked with MS SQL Server at one banking institution and PostgreSQL in another.
- Support in real time when needed.

Internship as a software developer | Qualitex Servicios Tecnológicos

January 2008 - March 2008 | Maracaibo, Venezuela

- Adjusting an in-house help desk/support ticket application to a different domain for Radio Marina de Venezuela.
- Existing software was designed for hardware and software technical support and needed to work for a company that provides support for communication and navigation equipment for the maritime activity.
- Assessing requirements directly with the contact person at Radio Marina de Venezuela.
- Worked with C# and MS SQL.

Cisco's Fundamentals of Java Programming teaching assistant | Universidad Rafael Belloso Chacín (URBE)

January 2007 - March 2008 | Maracaibo, Venezuela

- Teaching assistant of Cisco's Fundamentals of Java Programming course.
- Helping students with weekly assignments and case studies.
- Standing in for the instructor when needed.
- Organization and management of enrollments, workshops and conferences for the Technology Transfer Center.

Swimming instructor | Artes Swim Academy

August 2002 - August 2004 | Maracaibo, Venezuela

- Full-time work during the summer time as swimming instructor for children from 2.5 to 5 years old
- Providing special attention to children with Down syndrome.
- Assisting in other summer camp activities with young children.

Languages

Español: Native or bilingual proficiency. **English:** Native or bilingual proficiency. **Nederlands:** Elementary proficiency.

Hobbies

I enjoy cooking, baking and creating my own healthy and minimal recipes and posting them on my blog. I find writing very relaxing. Swimming is my favorite sport and I was part of a swimming team when I was younger. I also like flamenco dancing and singing. I'm very curious so I love to read about history and how things work.